EN (US)

English (United States)English (United Kingdom)English (Canada)English (Australia)Français (France)Français (Canada)日本語Español한국어Deutsch

* Products
* Solutions
* Resources
* Partners

EN (US)

English (United States)English (United Kingdom)English (Canada)English (Australia)Français (France)Français (Canada)日本語Español한국어Deutsch

Privacy Policy [Candidate Privacy Policy](https://www.verkada.com/privacy/candidate-privacy-policy/) [Cookie Policy](https://www.verkada.com/privacy/cookie-policy/) [Verkada Trust Hub](https://www.verkada.com/trust) [Data Subject Requests](https://verkada-privacy.relyance.ai/)

Privacy Policy

* Privacy Policy

Privacy Policy
==============

Last Revised: 20 September 2024

This Privacy Policy describes how Verkada Inc. and its subsidiaries and affiliates (collectively, “Verkada,” “Company,” “we”, “us” or “our”) collect, retain, use, and disclose your Personal Information (defined below) gathered through our [Website](https://www.verkada.com/) (“Site”), our in person and online interactions with you, and the hardware and software products we sell (“Products”), including our cloud-based platform, Command. This Privacy Policy is subject to and incorporates by reference our [Terms of Service](https://www.verkada.com/terms-of-service/).

As used in this Privacy Policy, Personal Information means information from which you may be identified directly (from that information alone) and indirectly (when different pieces of information are combined).

This Privacy Policy does not apply to information we process as a data processor or service provider on behalf of our customers. If you submit an inquiry to us regarding a job application, we will handle it in accordance with our [Candidate Privacy Policy](https://www.verkada.com/privacy/candidate-privacy-policy).

* When do we collect Personal Information?
    
    We collect Personal Information about you when:
    
    * you visit our Site or interact with other online content ("Online Interactions");
        
    * you request to purchase or use our Products ("Product Interactions"); or
        
    * we engage with you offline or via third-party sources ("Other Sources"). 

    We describe them further below and list the types of Personal Information collected in each.
    
    ### Online Interactions
    
    **When do we collect Personal Information from Online Interactions?**
    
    When you:
    
    * visit our website
        
    * request a demo or trial from us
        
    * register for a promotion or event  (e.g., webinar, training session, partner/reseller event) or schedule a meeting with us 
        
    * download materials from our Site (e.g., an eBook)
        
    * reach out to us via our online “Contact Us” form or otherwise communicate with us by email, phone, text or social media
        
    * provide reviews to us
        
    * subscribe to our marketing communications, including new product launches and newsletters

    **What we collect from Online Interactions:** 
    
    The type of Personal Information we collect from Online Interactions includes, but is not limited to:
    
    * your name
        
    * email address
        
    * physical address 
        
    * company
        
    * job title
        
    * payment details
        
    * phone number
        
    * IP address
        
    * MAC address
        
    * your communications, including any comments you provide to us

    Some of this Personal Information is collected from you directly when you provide it to us; some of it is collected automatically via cookies and similar technologies when you interact with the Site. For more information, please see our [Cookies Policy](https://www.verkada.com/privacy/cookie-policy). 
    
    **How we use Personal Information from Online Interactions:**
    
    We use the Personal Information we collect from Online Interactions to deliver our Site and Products to you, and carry out our legitimate interests of developing and growing our business, including to:
    
    * respond to your requests to receive further information from us, such as for a demo or to receive our online materials (e.g.,  eBooks) by using your name and email address 
        
    * send emails to you about the Products you have requested from us
        
    * send marketing materials to you via email, such as information about new Product launches, events, educational materials, new blog posts, newsletters, special offers and co-marketing efforts with our reseller partners (you may customize your email settings to [opt-out](https://www.verkada.com/emailsettings/) of receiving these marketing communications on our Site or via unsubscribe email links)
        
    * facilitate your attendance at training sessions, webinars or events by using Personal Information, such as your name, email address and work location
        
    * provide technical support and troubleshooting for the Site to identify technical issues and for security purposes 
        
    * administer our promotional offers and deliver prizes 
        
    * invite you to review our Site, Products and other online content
        
    * deliver advertising to you on other websites, for example, through using cookies and other similar technologies (see our [Cookies Policy](https://www.verkada.com/privacy/cookie-policy) for more)
        
    * analyze the impact of our advertising campaigns 
        
    * analyze the use of our Site and help customize your experience 
        
    * determine your location to deliver the Site in certain languages and any region- specific content
        
    * comply with applicable law where required or otherwise permitted

    provide it as needed to our partners and vendors who work with us (see also [Disclosure of Personal Information](#disclosureofpersonalinformation) section below)
    
    ### **Product Interactions**
    
    **When we collect Personal Information from Product Interactions**
    
    We collect your Personal Information from Product Interactions when you:
    
    * create an account on Command and provide contact and account information
        
    * submit requests through Command (e.g., support assistance)
        
    * engage with our internal resources, such as our knowledge base of user content 
        
    * log into, configure, use and manage your account and interact with our Products
        
    * send customer alerts (e.g., motion notifications, tamper alerts, etc.) generated by our Products

    We also collect your Personal Information when we enter into an agreement with you (or your company) for information about our Products (e.g., non-disclosure agreement) or to purchase them (e.g. End User Agreement) through our customer management software (e.g., Docusign and Ironclad).
    
    **What we collect from Product Interactions** 
    
    The type of Personal Information we collect from Product Interactions includes:
    
    * your name
        
    * email address
        
    * company name and organization name, (including any short names)
        
    * phone number
        
    * region
        
    * IP address
        
    * username
        
    * encrypted password
        
    * order history
        
    * telemetry information (e.g., usage, metrics, account Product and configuration information)

    **How we use Personal Information from Product Interactions:**
    
    We use the Personal Information we collect from Product Interactions to deliver our Products, develop and improve them, administer your Command account and for other purposes such as to:
    
    * authenticate your Command account information using your email address and encrypted password
        
    * better understand how users access and use our Products to improve their performance, customize your experience, and develop new products, features and functionality 
        
    * implement real-time responses to customer questions and support use cases
        
    * provide technical support and troubleshooting 
        
    * recommend product updates and offers to you
        
    * help secure and monitor our Products

    We also use your Personal Information when we process or enforce a transaction or legal agreements (e.g., our End User Agreement), invoices or orders.
    
    ### Other Sources
    
    **When we collect and use Personal Information from Other Sources**
    
    We may collect your Personal Information when you exchange business contact information with us at events or meetings (e.g., business cards), or if you visit one of our office locations.
    
    We may also collect your Personal Information through: (1) our partners (e.g., resellers); (2) third-party sources, including publicly available sources such as professional contact pages of company websites and social media sites, such as LinkedIn; or (3) companies who provide us with marketing services. Examples of third parties we work with include:
    
    * Apollo (see [Apollo's Privacy Center](https://www.apollo.io/company/privacy-center) for information about their privacy practices, including how to [opt-out](https://www.apollo.io/privacy-policy/remove))
        
    * ZoomInfo (see [ZoomInfo's Trust Center](https://www.zoominfo.com/trust-center) for information about their privacy practices, including how to [opt-out](https://privacyrequest.zoominfo.com/remove/verify))
        
    * Cognism (see [Cognism's Privacy Policy](https://www.cognism.com/en/privacy-policy) for more information about their privacy practices, including how to [opt-out](https://www.cognism.com/data-opt-out))

    The types of Personal Information we collect from other sources include your professional contact information (such as name, office address, email address, phone number).
    
    We use this information to send you material that we believe may be of interest to you, including news and offers about our products and services, where permissible.
    
    Our Site uses third-party platforms that offer advertising tracking features. If you visit our Site from an advertisement on a third-party platform, the platform provider may place a code on your browser that will help us understand the path you took to arrive on that page to measure the success of our ad campaigns.  For more information, see our [Cookie Policy](https://www.verkada.com/privacy/cookie-policy).
    
    We work with social media platforms and search engines, such as LinkedIn, Meta, Reddit and Google, to deliver targeted ads on their platforms.  We do this by: (1) matching our customers and prospects to those who are also users of these platforms; and (2) identifying individuals on these platforms who share common characteristics with our customers and prospects to create targeted audiences for our ads. These audiences may include current customers, prospects, Site visitors and Product users. 
    
    You can review and update how social media platforms use and share your data for these purposes. Please visit your social media platform privacy settings for more information.
    
    Command also uses third-party technologies, such as cookies, to measure the performance of our Apps and the Command website to help us develop and improve them. Metrics collected by these technologies are not used for advertising purposes.
    
    We may from time to time run a referral program. If you choose to participate by making a referral in this program, we will handle your Personal Information for the purposes of administering the program. Please see our program terms and conditions for further information.
    
* Disclosure of Personal Information
    
    We may disclose your Personal Information to:
    
    * Vendors, who are contractually bound to process any Personal Information solely on our behalf and according to our instructions. We may use vendors in order to:
        
        * help administer and improve the Site or provide our Products
            
        * personalize your experience on the Site or use of our Products 
            
        * process and fulfil orders including processing payments and shipping Products to you 
            
        * provide us with professional services including legal and financial services
            
        * provide analytics in our Apps and Command on our behalf 
            
        * track and analyze the performance and use of our Site 
            
        * provide security services
            
        * provide hosting, back-up and cloud storage solutions
            
        * provide advertising services and support our marketing campaigns
            
    * Third-party business partners, including resellers, who may co-sponsor or co-host events or conferences 
        
    * Our subsidiaries or affiliates
        
    * Third-party marketing partners who may provide you, on our behalf, with information relating to our Products or services that we believe you may find of interest, including showing you ads that are targeted to your interests. For more information please see our [Cookies Policy](https://www.verkada.com/privacy/cookie-policy). For information about opting out of interest-based advertising, see [NAI Consumer Opt Out](https://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1) or [YourAdChoices](https://youradchoices.com/control) resource centers
        
    * law enforcement, regulators, government agencies, courts or other third parties in response to legal process or where we believe disclosure is necessary (i) as a matter of applicable law or regulation, (ii) to exercise, establish or defend our legal rights, or (iii) to protect your vital interests or those of any other person
        
    * an actual or potential buyer (and its agents or advisers) in connection with any actual or proposed purchase, merger or acquisition of any part of our business, or to other third parties in the voluntary or involuntary dissolution (bankruptcy) of our business, provided that we inform the third party it must use your Personal Information only for the purposes disclosed in this Privacy Policy; and
        
    * any other person with your consent to the disclosure or as otherwise required or permitted by applicable law

* EEA, Switzerland and UK residents
    
    _Legal Basis for processing Personal Information_
    
    Our legal basis for processing the Personal Information described above will depend on the Personal Information concerned and the specific context in which we collect it. We may rely on the following legal bases for processing:
    
    We process Personal Information from you based on consent where appropriate, for example, depending on where you are located, prior to using cookies (see our [Cookie Policy](https://www.verkada.com/privacy/cookie-policy)). If we rely on your consent to process your Personal Information, we will ask for this before processing. 
    
    Where we are subject to a contract with you, we process your Personal Information on the basis that it is necessary for the performance of the contract or pre-contractual steps. If you do not provide the Personal Information required, we may not be able to perform the contract.
    
    We also process Personal Information on the basis of our legitimate interests. For example, to understand how you engage with us, deliver our Site and Products to you, troubleshoot, secure, develop and improve our Products or Site, determine your location to deliver the Site in certain languages and any region- specific content provide you with information you have requested from us or to respond to your requests such as signing up to an event or to receive content online (e.g., webinar, whitepaper, product demo) and to create and provide you access to your Command account. We may also process your Personal Information in relation to a contract with us, for example, when we notify you about changes to our services, fulfilling orders, sending invoices, and processing renewals. Where we rely on legitimate interests as our lawful basis for processing your Personal Information, we have also considered your rights and interests at the same time, and concluded that our interests are not overridden by your rights.
    
    In some cases, we may also have a legal obligation to process your Personal Information.
    
    _Data Transfer_
    
    Verkada has implemented safeguards to ensure an adequate level of data protection where your Personal Information is transferred outside of the EEA or UK, such as data processing agreements with our third party vendors and partners through which we implement the standard contractual clauses for the transfer of Personal Information as approved by the European Commission or other permitted mechanisms. Further details can be provided upon request.
    
    _Your Rights_
    
    You have the following data protection rights (depending on the context in which we process your information):
    
    * **Access:** You have the right to ask us for copies of your Personal Information. There are some exemptions, which means you may not always receive all the information we process. If you use Command, you can access your Personal Information through your Command account. 
        
    * **Erasure:** You have the right to ask us to erase your Personal Information in certain circumstances. You can access, amend, or delete your information, including Personal Information, through your Command account. Please contact Verkada Support at [\[email protected\]](https://www.verkada.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) if you have questions regarding how to delete your account or information associated with it.
        
    * **Rectification:** You have the right to ask us to rectify information you think is inaccurate and to complete information you think is incomplete. If you use Command, you can amend your Personal Information held on Command through your Command account.
        
    * **Object / Restrict Processing / Request Portability:** In certain circumstances, you can object to processing of your Personal Information, ask us to restrict processing of your Personal Information or request portability of your Personal Information. 
        
    * **Opt-out of Marketing Communications:** You have the right to opt-out of marketing communications we send you at any time [on our website](https://www.verkada.com/emailsettings/). 
        
    * **Withdraw Your Consent**: Similarly, if we have collected and processed your Personal Information with your consent, you can withdraw your consent at any time. Withdrawing your consent will not affect the lawfulness of any processing we conducted prior to your withdrawal, nor will it affect the processing of your personal information conducted in reliance on lawful processing grounds other than consent.

    You can request to exercise any of your privacy rights above by contacting us at [\[email protected\]](https://www.verkada.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection). You also have the right to complain to a data protection authority about our collection and use of your Personal Information. For more information, please contact your local data protection authority. For Europe please see [here](https://www.edpb.europa.eu/about-edpb/about-edpb/members_en), for Switzerland [here](https://www.edoeb.admin.ch/edoeb/en/home.html)  and for the UK, [here](https://ico.org.uk/).
    
* California Residents
    
    The California Consumer Privacy Act (“CCPA”) requires us to disclose information regarding the categories of personal information and sensitive personal information that we have collected about California consumers, the categories of sources from which the information was collected, the business or commercial purposes (as those terms are defined by applicable law) for which the information was collected, and the categories of parties to whom we disclose personal information. As used in this section, “personal information” shall have the meaning set forth in the CCPA.
    
    Throughout this Privacy Policy, we describe the specific pieces of personal information and sensitive personal information we collect, the sources of that information, and how we share it. Under the CCPA, we also have to provide you with the "categories" of personal information and sensitive personal information we collect and disclose for “business or commercial purposes” (as those terms are defined by the CCPA). 
    
    In the twelve months leading up to the effective date of this Privacy Policy, we have collected and disclosed the categories of personal information described in [When do we collect Personal Information?](#whendowecollectpersonalinformation) The categories of personal information are: identifiers (such as name, address, and email address); commercial information (such as transaction data); financial data (such as credit card and other financial account information); internet or other network or device activity (such as IP address); professional or employment-related information (such as your current employer and job title); general location information (such as inferred from an IP address); inference data about you (such as if we derive information about your role within a company); audio and visual information (such as when you call into customer service or visit our offices); and other information that identifies or can be reasonably associated with you. 
    
    The categories of sensitive personal information are account log-in and password or other credentials allowing access to your account.
    
    We process the categories of personal information identified above for the purposes as described in more detail in [When do we collect Personal Information?](#whendowecollectpersonalinformation) 
    
    We collect the categories of personal information identified above from the following sources: (1) directly from you; (2) through your use of the Products; and (3) other parties (e.g., other users) and unaffiliated parties.
    
    We describe our information disclosure practices in more detail in the section above on [Disclosure of Personal Information](#disclosureofpersonalinformation).
    
    _“Sale” and “Sharing” of Personal Information_
    
    The CCPA sets forth certain obligations for businesses that “sell” or “share” personal information. Where we refer to “sell” or “share” (or their variants) in quotes, we are referring to those terms as uniquely defined in the CCPA.
    
    We may use third-party analytics services and online advertising services that may result in the “sharing” of online identifiers and other identifiers (e.g., cookie data, IP addresses, device identifiers, general location information, usage information, email addresses) with analytics partners to help us analyze and understand use of the Site and our Products and to advertise the Products on other websites. In some cases, such practice may also constitute a “sale” of personal information under the CCPA. If you or your authorized agent would like to opt out of our “sharing” or “sale” of your information for such purposes, you may do so by clicking Your Privacy Choices on the footer of the Site. To opt-out of the “sharing” or “sale” of personal information that is not based on cookies or other tracking technologies, please contact [\[email protected\]](https://www.verkada.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).  For more information, see our [Cookies Policy](https://www.verkada.com/privacy/cookie-policy). For clarity, if you’ve provided consent to receive text messages from us, we do not share that consent with unaffiliated third parties for their own use unless you have consented to that disclosure.
    
    Please note that we also respond to and abide by opt-out preference signals sent through the Global Privacy Control. Any opt-out preferences you have exercised through these methods will only apply to the specific device/browser on which you made them.  For more information on how to use the Global Privacy Control, see [www.globalprivacycontrol.org](http://www.globalprivacycontrol.org/).
    
    We do not knowingly “sell” or “share” the personal information of children under 16.
    
    _Do Not Track Disclosure_
    
    We do not respond to browser-initiated Do Not Track signals, as the Internet industry is currently still working on Do Not Track standards, implementations, and solutions. Please note that Do Not Track is a different privacy mechanism than the Global Privacy Control browser choice referenced above.
    
    _Retention of Your Personal Information_
    
    Please see the [Data Retention](#dataretention) section below.
    
    _CCPA Rights_
    
    If you are a California resident, you may have certain rights. California law may permit you to request that we:
    
    * provide you the categories of personal information we have collected or disclosed about you; the categories of sources of such information; the business or commercial purpose for collecting, “selling,” or “sharing” your personal information; the categories of third parties to whom we disclose or “sell,” or with whom we “share,” personal information; and the categories of personal information we “sell” or “share”
        
    * provide access to and/or a copy of certain information we hold about you
        
    * delete certain information we have about you
        
    * correct inaccurate personal information that we maintain about you

    You may also have the right to receive information about the financial incentives that we offer to you, if any, and the right to not be discriminated against (as provided for in applicable law) for exercising certain of your rights.
    
    Some information may be exempt from these rights under applicable law. We may also need certain types of information in order to provide you with our Products or services, and if you ask us to delete it, you may no longer be able to access or use them.  If you would like to exercise any of these rights, please submit a request at [\[email protected\]](https://www.verkada.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) or call 833.280.5900. You will be required to verify your identity before we fulfill your request. To do so, you will need to provide the information identified in the webform or as otherwise directed by us. You can also designate an authorized agent to make a request on your behalf. To do so, you must provide us with written authorization or a power of attorney, signed by you, for the agent to act on your behalf. You may still need to verify your identity directly with us.
    
    The CCPA also allows you to limit the use or disclosure of your “sensitive personal information” (as defined in the CCPA) if your sensitive personal information is used for certain purposes. Please note that we do not use or disclose sensitive personal information in ways that create an opt-out right.
    
    Please see the [Candidate Privacy Policy](https://www.verkada.com/privacy/candidate-privacy-policy#californiaresidents) for information on how we handle Personal Information Collected with regard to a job application.
    
* Opt-out of Marketing Communications
    
    You  can  opt-out of marketing communications we send you at any time. You can do this by following the opt-out link or instructions contained in any such email or by visiting [our website](https://www.verkada.com/emailsettings/) and following the instructions listed there. To opt-out of other forms of marketing (e.g., postal marketing), please contact us at [\[email protected\]](https://www.verkada.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection). Please note that it may take a few business days for us to process opt-out requests and we will need to retain your Personal Information on a suppression list to honor your opt-out request. 
    
    If you opt-out of receiving marketing emails or promotions, we will still send you service-based emails where requested by you or to service your account and emails to facilitate a transaction.
    
* Third-party Links
    
    The Site contains links to other, third-party websites. Any access to and use of such linked websites is not governed by this Privacy Policy, but, instead, is governed by the privacy policies of those third-party websites. We are not responsible for the information practices of such third-party websites.
    
* Where your Personal Information is stored and processed
    
    Your Personal Information may be transferred to, and processed in, countries other than the country in which you are resident. These countries may have data protection laws that are different from the laws of your country (and, in some cases, may not be as protective) and data may be accessible to law enforcement and national security authorities under certain circumstances. The Site is primarily hosted in the United States.
    
    By providing your Personal Information to Verkada, you acknowledge the transfer of your information to the United States for storage, use, processing, maintenance, and onward transfer of such information to other entities, regardless of their location. However, such activities will be done in accordance with this Privacy Policy. 
    
    Third parties that we work with may also process your Personal Information in the U.S. and / or facilitate the transfer of or access to your Personal Information outside of the U.S. We will take steps to require them to process your Personal Information subject to appropriate safeguards (for example, implementing standard contractual clauses where appropriate).
    
* Data Retention
    
    We retain Personal Information we collect from you for the time necessary for the purposes for which it is processed, including where we have an ongoing legitimate business need to do so (for example, to provide you with a service you have requested) or to comply with applicable legal, tax or accounting requirements or as otherwise required by applicable laws and regulations.
    
* Children and Minors
    
    The Site and Products are not directed to individuals under the age of 18 and we do not knowingly collect information from anyone under 18. If you become aware that a child has provided us with Personal Information, please contact us at [\[email protected\]](https://www.verkada.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) If we become aware that a child under 18 has provided us with Personal Information, we will take steps to delete such information as soon as possible as required under applicable laws.
    
* Updates to this Privacy Policy
    
    We may update this Privacy Policy from time to time in response to changing legal, technical or business developments. When we update our Privacy Policy, we will take appropriate measures to inform you consistent with the significance of the changes we make and as required by applicable law. Please check back from time to time to review the current Privacy Policy, which is effective as of the revision date listed above.
    
* How we protect your Personal Information
    
    We use technical and organizational measures to help safeguard your Personal Information from unauthorized access, use, loss, alteration, destruction, modification or other malicious actions, and take steps to limit access to your Personal Information on a “need to know” basis with those who process it in accordance with this Privacy Policy.  We take steps to contractually require our vendors and other third parties with whom we work to protect any Personal Information they process on our behalf.  For more information about our security practices, please visit the [Trust Center](https://www.verkada.com/trust/).
    
* How to Contact Us
    
    We encourage your questions and comments about any privacy concerns. Please direct any privacy related questions or comments to [\[email protected\]](https://www.verkada.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)
    
    Verkada Inc. is a controller from which you buy Products and services (depending on where you are in the world).  It administers and hosts this site, and makes global and strategic decisions about them as the parent company and global HQ.
    
    Verkada Inc. is located at 406 E 3rd Ave, San Mateo, CA 94401 
    
    Verkada Limited and VERKADA POLAND SPÓŁKA Z OGRANICZONĄ ODPOWIEDZIALNOŚCIĄ may also be data controllers in their capacity as our European entities which help develop and grow our business locally.
    
    For office addresses of  global Verkada company offices, please see the [directory](https://www.verkada.com/contact/) of our office locations.

* Company

* Products

* Support

* Newsroom

EN (US)

English (United States)English (United Kingdom)English (Canada)English (Australia)Français (France)Français (Canada)日本語Español한국어Deutsch

United States & Canada

Global phone numbers

United Kingdom

France

Australia

Benelux

Latin America

Japan

South Korea (hide)

Singapore

© Copyright 2024 Verkada Inc. All rights reserved.
